-We sit in the middle of the firing line and you will get an example of how it sounds here.
If we are to get some decent sound, we can sit in the caravan.
It is difficult to explain Speed Weekend for those who have not been here.
There are so many different vehicles and people who appreciate this weekend once a year.
This is the third year we are running with this.
The first year it had original wheel suspension.
I had skates mounted on the tires.
But then I only came 150 meters before it started wobbling so I keep overturning.
Last year it was rebuilt with a scooter and own swing at the back with the skate.
Now it is stable.
Now I am looking for more effect so I can go faster.
-What do you have average speed?
I had problems with the charge pressure control on the straight stretch.
It could not hold on to properly ...
... I would only have charging pressure on 2.5 bar.
But the charging pressure was 2.7-2.8 bar all the time.
So I had about 100 hp too much.
We knew it would not endure.
And it didn't.
The top cover gasket went, the top cap Sprak and holes in the valve.
We'll see what I can find until next year.
It's just starting over.
-So you packed up?
We tore the engine yesterday to see if it was rescued.
We thought it was just the top lid gasket first.
-Her God, on a lawnmower!
It should go faster.
-How is it to drive?
It is very high.
It's not like a go -kart because you sit high up.
Yes it feels because it is a high weight point and it jasses when driving.
The feeling is sometimes that it can overturn.
The last round I drove I kept running over the photocell.
The front wheels are not often in the ground.
So you have to plan if you are to turn.
It's fun, a terrified delight.
-Why Speed Weekend?
I saw that Hubbe Berg had built a garden tractor.
I was influenced and thought it was a cool thing.
It is well thanks to him.
It's a great event this.
I like things like this and I compete for myself.
-Is only me who thinks this looks fatal?
Stop, stop, stop !!
We lift the whole car.
It should fit another car then.
That car has survived so far.
But, well uh ..
You should have fun loading.
-It looked scary.
Yes, the idea was good.
Just after I take this picture, the ramp folded.
We had to strengthen the ramp below.
Now the ramps weigh 60 kg each.
You learn as long as you live.
And if it goes to hell, it goes to hell.
It is quite easy to change the gearbox here.
Yes, do you change it now?
The fired would be quick to build.
But unfortunately, there was geek at the detail level in this case as well.
I would guess that it has taken 200-300 hours to build it.
100 km/h is the magic no for all my vehicles.
Faster than 105.2 km/h I would like to go because it did Mobacken Racing a long time ago.
It would be a milestone to beat their record.
-We can comment on how much it sounds?
-How long away can we be 300 meters?
We are enough.
300 meters in from and now the black hole will start the pulse jet the scooter.
I think we do.
Above all, it feels in the body.
I know it is heard all the way to Sandviken.
(1.5 miles)
It is great fun guys who offer themselves.
We have to check how long they will come.
As a currios, the engine type has not been used since the 1940s to something sensible.
And it was not used for anything sensible in the 40s either for the Germans it had for the V1 missile.
Well, that's the most famous ...
... the application that has used large pulse dough engines.
They were used with varying success.
The Germans shot many towards England and some arrived.
The V1 missile was called "Buzz Bomb" because of how they sound.
There are probably still people who were involved and can testify to the sound.
It was probably quite horror I can imagine.
This engine we have I think it differs 10% on traction.
Basically simple but then it gets complicated when you peel it up.
Especially with the durability.
The biggest problem the last few years is to get the engine brackets to hold together.
The engine becomes 4-5 cm longer when it is warm and then also increases the diameter.
So it is wearing the engine brackets.
What looks good is that we have not found any damage to neither the brackets nor the engine after this weekend.
And it feels good.
We made no performance increases for this year, but put all the energy on the engine brackets.
And it seems to have succeeded.
We get a salary for the effort when sitting in the CAD program and calling and discussing.
There will be a lot of debate in between.
And usually it will be good.
Warning signal, thank you!